majestic.co.uk 2016-03-19

# Privacy & Cookies - Information - Majestic Wine

Majestic is committed to respecting and protecting our customers' privacy. We will only use the information that we collect about you lawfully in accordance with such legislation as the Data Protection Act 1998 and Directive on Privacy and Electronic Communications 2003.

### Your personal details

When you register on our website or provide us with your details in-store we will collect some of your personal details. You may choose to be added to our postal mailing list to receive our seasonal promotions, and also may subscribe to email newsletters. The information we collect is just for Majestic Wine Warehouses Ltd and other companies in the Majestic Wine PLC group: we do not release your information to third parties (other than where necessary to perform a service, such as courier companies carrying out deliveries). We will not email you unless you have given us your consent, and you have the option not to be included and to remove yourself from our mailing lists at any time.

We collect information about you for two reasons: firstly, to process your order and second, to provide you with the best possible service. The type of information we may collect about you includes:

  * Your name
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Credit/debit card details
  * Your previous purchase history

We will never collect sensitive information about you without your explicit consent. The information we hold will be accurate and up to date. You can check the information that we hold about you by emailing us at [info@majestic.co.uk](mailto:info@majestic.co.uk). If you find any inaccuracies we will delete or correct it promptly.

The personal information which we hold will be held securely in accordance with our internal security policy and the law. Information may be transferred outside the European Economic Area to the United States of America (where our agents will operate under European Union Safe Harbor Framework). By submitting your information, you consent to this transfer.

### Crime prevention

For the purposes of the prevention or detection of offences, and/or the apprehension or prosecution of offenders, we may share any information that we collect with the Police, other public or private sector agencies or representative bodies in accordance with the relevant legislation. Information shared in this way will not be used for marketing purposes.

Please be aware that CCTV is in operation in all our stores and at our head office and delivery depot.

### Cookies and online privacy

In common with most websites, majestic.co.uk uses "cookies". Cookies are small snippets of text that are stored on your computer. When you request a page from our website, the cookies are sent to our web server, and when we send a page back to you our server may add to or change these cookies. Without cookies, we would not be able to know that you are the same person from page to page. We do not store anything that could identify you personally in cookies; instead we store codes and references which can only be connected to your personal details by our own systems.

We use cookies for a variety of reasons, such as remembering the contents of your shopping trolley, your preferences such as your local store, and displaying the products you've recently viewed. We also use analytics software, which allows us to track and measure patterns of behaviour among our users so that we can improve our website.

Additionally, we have partnerships with some carefully chosen third party services which involve including some code on our website, for example so that we can jointly measure the effectiveness of our marketing activities or enable you to share content with your friends. In some cases these partners may also store and retrieve their own cookies on your computer. Cookies set by websites other than majestic.co.uk are known as "third party cookies".

In accordance with the Directive on Privacy and Electronic Communications 2003, and to be as open and transparent as possible, we have provided more information on the cookies in use on majestic.co.uk here (including our blog at blog.majestic.co.uk and Careers website at careers.majestic.co.uk). These details may change over time as we continue to develop our website, and we are investing in finding ways to reduce our use of cookies whilst continuing to deliver the best experience possible for our customers.

We have grouped our cookies into four categories:

  1. **Strictly Necessary** : these cookies are essential to the operation of our site.
  2. **Performance** : these cookies allow us to monitor the performance of our website in a non-personally identifiable way.
  3. **Functionality** : these cookies allow us to add services to enhance user experience and remember settings, but will not be used by third parties to track you personally.
  4. **Targeting** : these cookies are used by third parties to provide services, such as social networks and advertising networks who may use the information obtained to serve relevant adverts to you.

You can change the settings in your web browser to allow or deny different websites from setting cookies. Please note that disabling "first party cookies" from majestic.co.uk will affect the successful functioning of the site, and you will not be able to use the shopping trolley or checkout. For more information on cookies, see [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

#### Majestic.co.uk session cookies

'Session' cookies are temporary and are deleted when you close your web browser.

Cookie name | Privacy Rating | Cookie details  
---|---|---  
33cms_session  
33cms_csrf_cookie_name  
HBR_SITE_SESSID  
hidden  
PHPSESSID | Strictly Necessary | These cookies are used only by our Careers website ([careers.majestic.co.uk](http://careers.majestic.co.uk/)) to store essential information for tracking your job applications.  
AODSESSION  
X-Mapping-gbooldlg | Strictly Necessary | Used to store essential information for tracking your shopping trolley and distributing requests across our various web servers.  
s_cc  
s_sq  
s_evar8 | Performance | These cookies are used by Adobe SiteCatalyst, which is software we use to track the performance of our website by measuring such things as how many visitors we receive, whether they have responded to some of our advertising, which pages are most requested, and which products are purchased. We use this data to identify issues and improve our website. No personally identifiable information is included. The data generated is only available to selected Majestic and Adobe staff.  
__utmc | Performance | This cookies is used by Google Analytics, which is software we use to track the performance of our website by measuring such things as how many visitors we receive, whether they have responded to some of our advertising, which pages are most requested, and which products are purchased. We use this data to identify issues and improve our website. No personally identifiable information is included. The data generated is only available to selected Majestic and Google staff.  
chosen-view | Functionality | Used to remember your preferred type of display for product listings (list or grid).  
popover | Functionality | Used to remember if we have shown you a 'popover' message during this visit to the website.  
maj-bstrip-closed | Functionality | Used to remember if we have shown you a message asking where you would like delivery or collection.  
  
#### Majestic.co.uk persistent cookies

'Persistent' cookies are not deleted when you close your web browser; they are saved and used across multiple browsing sessions.

Cookie name | Privacy Rating | Cookie details  
---|---|---  
33cms_csrf_cookie_name | Strictly Necessary | This cookie is used only by our Careers website ([careers.majestic.co.uk](http://careers.majestic.co.uk/)) to provide security to protect us against hacking attacks.  
cookie-check | Strictly Necessary | This cookie is used to remember that you have confirmed our warning about the use of cookies.  
gpv_p10  
s_vi | Performance | These cookies are used by Adobe SiteCatalyst, which is software we use to track the performance of our website by measuring such things as how many visitors we receive, whether they have responded to some of our advertising, which pages are most requested, and which products are purchased. We use this data to identify issues and improve our website. No personally identifiable information is included. The data generated is only available to selected Majestic and Adobe staff.  
mbox | Performance | This cookie is used by Adobe Recommendations, which is software we use to display recommended alternative products on our product pages and the trolley page. No personally identifiable information is included. The data generated is only available to selected Majestic and Adobe staff.  
__utma  
__utmb  
__utmz | Performance | These cookies are used by Google Analytics, which is software we use to track the performance of our website by measuring such things as how many visitors we receive, whether they have responded to some of our advertising, which pages are most requested, and which products are purchased. We use this data to identify issues and improve our website. No personally identifiable information is included. The data generated is only available to selected Majestic and Google staff.  
maj-welcomed | Functionality | Used to record that certain events have occurred, such as the fact that we have shown you our "New to Majestic?" content, so that we can tailor the content we show you accordingly.  
MSID | Functionality | Used to store some information we use to personalise your experience each time you visit our site, such as your local store.  
  
#### Third-party cookies

As you browse our website, we sometimes include content that comes from websites other than Majestic. For example, the Facebook 'Like' button is displayed by Facebook's servers, not Majestic's. On these occasions, that website may read or set their own cookies on your browser. We are working to reduce the amount of third-party cookies set as you browse our website to a minimum.

Third-party site | Privacy Rating | Details  
---|---|---  
datacash.com | Strictly necessary | The payment form on our checkout is hosted by our payment service provider, DataCash. This avoids the need for us to capture your card details and submit them separately to DataCash, improving the security of your online shopping. The JSESSIONID cookie that is set during this process is used solely to ensure that if the form has to re-display (such as when there is an error in your payment details) DataCash can identify your browsing session, and is deleted when you close your web browser. Your card details are never stored in the cookie.  
awin1.com | Targeting | Affiliate Window are an affiliate network. Affiliates display advertising for companies and are rewarded when customers visit or shop on the advertiser's website. Our order confirmation page notifies Affiliate Window of transactions so that they can determine whether the order should be credited to a particular affiliate. No personally identifiable information is stored in the cookie. Affiliate Window have their own [privacy policy](http://www.affiliatewindow.com/documents/Privacy%20Policy.pdf).  
bizrate.com | Targeting | Bizrate is owned by Yahoo! Our order confirmation page notifies BizRate of transactions so that we can track the effectiveness of our advertising on the Yahoo! search marketing network. Yahoo! Search Marketing has its own [privacy policy](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/uk/yahoo/searchmarketing/details.html).  
doubleclick.net | Targeting | DoubleClick is owned by Google. Our order confirmation page also notifies Google of transactions so that we can monitor the effectiveness of our advertising on Google. Google has its own [privacy policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en-GB/policies/).  
facebook.com | Targeting | We may display "Like" and "Share" buttons so that customers can share our content on Facebook. These buttons are displayed by Facebook's servers, and by using cookies Facebook is able to detect if you are a logged-in Facebook user. Facebook has its own [privacy policy](http://twitter.com/privacy).  
google.com  
googleadservices.com | Targeting | Our Store Locator displays maps from Google. We may display the "+1" button so that customers can share our content on the Google +1 network. These buttons are displayed by Google's servers, and by using cookies Google is able to detect if you are a logged-in Google user. Our order confirmation page also notifies Google of transactions so that we can monitor the effectiveness of our advertising on Google. Google has its own [privacy policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en-GB/policies/).  
msn.com | Targeting | Our order confirmation page notifies Microsoft of transactions so that we can monitor the effectiveness of our advertising on the Microsoft Advertising network. Microsoft has its own [privacy policy](http://privacy.microsoft.com/en-gb/fullnotice.mspx).  
overture.com | Targeting | Overture is owned by Yahoo! Our order confirmation page notifies Yahoo! of transactions so that we can track the effectiveness of our advertising on the Yahoo! search marketing network. Yahoo! Search Marketing has its own [privacy policy](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/uk/yahoo/searchmarketing/details.html).  
quantserve.com | Targeting | Our blog at [blog.majestic.co.uk](http://www.blog.majestic.co.uk/) is hosted by Wordpress.com. Wordpress's automatically generated code uses QuantServe to track page views. QuantServe is provided by Quantcast, who aggregate tracking data from various websites and provide services to those websites to serve targeted adverts based on your browsing history. No personally identifiable information is included, but since QuantServe tracking exists on various websites, Quantcast can identify patterns in individuals' web browsing. Quantcast provides an [opt-out page](http://www.quantcast.com/how-we-do-it/consumer-choice/opt-out) so you can ensure that visits from your web browser will not be tracked. We are working to remove this tracking from our blog as soon as possible.  
scorecardresearch.com | Targeting | Our blog at [blog.majestic.co.uk](http://www.blog.majestic.co.uk/) is hosted by Wordpress.com. Wordpress's automatically generated code uses Scorecard Research to track page views. Scorecard Research is provided by ComScore, a market research company, who aggregate anonymous tracking data from various websites and sell the information gathered to companies for a charge. No personally identifiable information is included, but since Scorecard Research tracking exists on various websites, ComScore can identify patterns in individuals' web browsing. Scorecard Research provides a [preferences page](http://www.scorecardresearch.com/preferences.aspx) so you can ensure that visits from your web browser will not be tracked. We are working to remove this tracking from our blog as soon as possible.  
twitter.com  
twimg.com | Targeting | We may display "Tweet" and "Follow" buttons so that customers can share our content on Twitter. These buttons are displayed by Twitter's servers, and by using cookies Twitter is able to detect if you are a logged-in Twitter user. Twitter has its own [privacy policy](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).  
wordpress.com | Targeting | Our blog at [blog.majestic.co.uk](http://www.blog.majestic.co.uk/) is hosted by Wordpress.com, a widely-used blogging platform owned by Automattic and covered by Automattic's [privacy policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/). By using cookies, Wordpress is able to detect if you are a logged-in Wordpress user. Wordpress also generates statistics which we use to help track the performance of our blog by measuring such things as how many visitors we receive and which posts are most requested. No personally identifiable information is included. The data generated is only available to selected Majestic and Automattic staff.  
yahoo.com | Targeting | Our order confirmation page notifies Yahoo! of transactions so that we can monitor the effectiveness of our advertising on the Yahoo! search marketing network. Yahoo! Search Marketing has its own [privacy policy](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/uk/yahoo/searchmarketing/details.html).  
youtube.com  
ytimg.com | Targeting | We may embed videos into our website from YouTube. By using cookies YouTube is able to detect if you are a logged-in YouTube user. YouTube is owned by Google and is covered by Google's [privacy policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en-GB/policies/).  
Fast Thinking  
| Targeting | Fast Thinking delivers more relevant advertising experiences by retargeting website visitors with different adverts according to the content viewed or the products bought. No personally identifiable data is stored by Fast Thinking  
Digilant  
| Targeting | Fast Thinking use an advertising buying platform called Digilant in order to retarget advertising to visitors to our website. No personally identifiable data is stored by Digilant  
  
### Email Tracking

Some emails we send include tracking codes so that we can tell how many people open and click on links in those emails. Usually this information is used for aggregated statistics, but we can also track, at an individual level, whether a particular user has opened and clicked on an email. Using cookies as described above we can also determine if a particular user has completed a transaction. Sometimes we use this information to re-email people who didn't click the first time, or who did or didn't complete a purchase. If you want to be sure that none of your email activity is tracked in this way then you should not subscribe to our email mailing list. Existing subscribers can unsubscribe using the link at the bottom of every marketing email we send.

If you have any further questions about this, please email us at [info@majestic.co.uk](mailto:info@majestic.co.uk) and we will be happy to help.
